Welcome to Yahoo Finance's flagship
show, The Morning Brief. I'm Julie
Hyman. Let's get to the three things you
need to know today. First up, US stock
futures rebounding this morning after
the major averages sold off in Tuesday's
trade. Despite the modest pullback,
stocks are still trading near record
highs. The S&P 500 has now gone 107
sessions without a drop of at least 2%.
That's its longest stretch since July
2024. Tech stocks bore the brunt of
selling on Tuesday, but they are
rebounding amid some renewed AI
optimism. Some of that is coming from
Micron earnings. The memory chipmaker
gave an upbeat outlook driven by demand
for AI equipment. Shares of the company
have nearly doubled this year and the
latest results are further bolstering
investor optimism. We're seeing a little
bit of wavering in the shares after that
big run we've seen this year. And
Alibaba soaring to a 4-year high after
unveiling its AI plans. CEO Eddie Woo
said the company will ramp up AI
spending above an original target of $50
billion. The e-commerce giant made the
announcement at its annual technology
conference. It also revealed a software
partnership with, of course, Nvidia.
[Music]
Let's get a check in on stock futures
here this morning. So, all three major
averages pointing to a slightly higher
open here. We've got the Nasdaq leading
those early gains, indicating a rise of
about a quarter percent at the open with
the Dow and the S&P 500 participating as
well. Let's dig into our top stories of
the day. Futures are indeed higher as
stocks look to recover losses from that
prior session. Plus, JPAL keeping his
options open as he warns of the Federal
Reserve's quote challenging situation
and Alibaba soaring as it bets big on
AI. Joining me now, senior reporter
Brook Depal live at the NASDAQ, Federal
Reserve correspondent Jennifer
Sharonburgger and Morning Brief Market
Sunrise host Ramzan Carmali. Um, let's
start with you, Brooke. And looking at
this backdrop for stocks where yes, we
saw some wavering yesterday, but now
perhaps a resumption of that push to
highs,
Julie, we were on quite the hot streak
there. Record setting hot streak,
especially heading into Monday's close.
And after we did see that momentum, the
third straight day of record high closes
on Tuesday, we did see all three major
indices slide slowly uh slightly lower
uh than those record highs all closing
in the group uh the red rather on
Tuesday afternoon. And now you could see
here we are gaining some momentum this
morning largely led by Micron largely
led by this AI trade rally and some
renewed optimism that the Federal
Reserve will cut interest rates in this
year. We did hear from Fed chair Jerome
Pal on Tuesday and he did suggest that
equities were highly valued right now
and so investors really tried to digest
that. that led to a lower close on
Tuesday and now we're seeing some
renewed optimism to kick off this
Wednesday's trading session.
>> Yeah. And let's talk about some of the
sources of that optimism, guys. Um
Ramson, you know, there has been this
interesting sort of stutter start, if
you will, with AI sentiment, right?
Where people get very excited and then
they're like, "Wait a minute, is it
really that big of a deal?" And then
something new happens and they get
excited again. And this morning, Alibaba
seems to be the upward catalyst, or at
least one of them.
It c certainly is. So the the Chinese
tech giant, it's unveiled a sweeping AI
push and it'll be partnering with Nvidia
to build cuttingedge AI infrastructure
and rolling out its Quen 3 Max language
model. Now investors love the news. The
Hong Kong listed stock jumped close to
more than 9% high. In fact, at one point
during the day, it hit a 4year intraday
high as well. And keep in mind trading
volumes in Hong Kong were pretty low
because um much lower than usual anyway
because the city's bracing itself for
the impact of the super typhoon regassa
as well. So that's even more impressive.
And as you can see in the pre-market uh
ADR shares, they're up almost 9% in New
York as well. Now Alpha Alibaba CEO
Eddie Woo said that demand for AI has
blown past expectations and he's pledged
to invest $50 billion for global
expansion. But like other Chinese
companies, Alibaba does face a bit of a
dilemma over access to Nvidia's AI
processors, which they need to train
advanced models. Now, Beijing is pushing
the country's tech firms like Alibaba to
wean themselves off Nvidia's AI chips,
nearly all of which are blocked by US
export controls. It's also worth noting
that Alibaba's ADRs, which are listed in
New York, as I said, well, they're
trading back at levels from four years
ago, but they're still about half of
what they were 5 years ago.
And shares in China and Hong Kong though
definitely did get a boost overall in
this news. Both the Hangen and the
Shanghai Composite are up sharply today.
And in fact, Asian stocks are trading
near four-year highs and remain on track
this month for their best monthly
performance in a year. I mean, Julie,
who said that September was meant to be
a poor month for stocks?
>> Yeah. Well, there's a few days left.
Don't don't jinx it, guys. Uh Brooke,
let's talk about the other AI driven
story that we are watching this morning.
And that is Micron. The shares initially
were higher after it reported after the
close. They have been wavering a little
bit.
Yeah, we did get a pop in uh after
market close on W or Tuesday. And now
we're seeing that reverse just a bit to
the downside down about 5 cents a
percent after this runup that this
company has had year to date. But the
memory chipmaker, which is used
alongside those Nvidia A uh Nvidia chips
in these AI data centers, beat on both
the top and bottom line. And that did
drive some renewed optimism about what
exactly this momentum, this AI trade
rally could be. So Micron beat them both
the top and bottom line. Their fiscal
fourth quarter revenue came in, as you
can see on your screen, at 11.3 billion.
That was more than the street had
expected. Adjusted earnings also beat as
well, coming in at $3.3. Also higher
than what the street has expected. And
it was this this outlook, this guidance
for the first quarter that also got Wall
Street excited perhaps. The CEO saying
on the call that over the coming years
they expect to trillions of dollars to
be invested in AI and a significant
portion of that they say will be spent
on memory, their key business there. And
there was this hope, this optimism on
the street overnight. We did see six
firms raise their price targets this
morning in the early hours of this
morning. That includes Barclays. That
also includes Key Bank as well as Piper
Sandlers. You could see there most of
them gearing towards that $200 price
point. We also heard from Wedbush,
Needam, and Rosenblats. They also raise
their uh price targets as well. And I do
want to point out that Rosenlat now has
the highest price target on the street
of $250. And if you take a look at where
the stock stands now at $165, that would
be an $100 additional value. And so
really waiting to see this momentum that
continues behind this stock. As you can
see, it's had quite the rally,
especially over these key summer months.
>> Yeah, we're going to dig more into what
the company is doing in the next hour.
Um, and then we also have to talk about
um a speech or speeches, I guess, that
happened yesterday. We were talking a
lot about uh Jerome Pal and his speech,
but there were also some other Fed
officials that we need to talk about as
well, right, Jen?
>> Yeah, that's right, Julie. Uh, Fed Chair
J. Pal not offering too much new in his
speech on Tuesday. Very non-committal on
the policy front, reiterating that the
balance of risks have shifted and that's
why the Fed cut rates that rates are
still modestly restrictive and that the
Fed's not on a preset course. Pal
reiterated that given the challenges to
both sides of the dual mandate, both on
employment and inflation, there is no
risk-free path for policy. But perhaps
the more interesting remarks on Tuesday
came from Fed Governor Michelle Bowman,
who said she is more concerned about
weakness in the labor market and the
economy, less concerned about inflation,
and wants to take preemptive action to
support the job market. She said she's
gaining confidence that the impact of
tariffs on inflation are not going to
lead to longerlasting inflation. In
fact, she said she thinks lower
immigration could a actually push down
inflation. An argument we have heard
from new Fed Governor Stephen Myron. Uh
but she warned that the job market has
become fragile and could deteriorate
significantly. Those are her words in
the coming months. And I just want to
read a passage from her speech yesterday
where she said, quote, "In my view, the
recent data, including the estimated
payroll employment benchmark revisions,
show that we are at serious risk of
already being behind the curve and
addressing deteriorating labor market
conditions. Should these conditions
continue, I am concerned that we will
need to adjust policy at a faster pace
and to a larger degree going forward."
So all eyes on her and perhaps that next
jobs report due out on October 3rd.
Bowman also went as far as to say that
the Fed is too data point dependent and
that data is inherently backwardlooking
and can put the Fed behind the curve and
that the Fed should be more
forward-looking, an approach that she
plans to take and one that the
administration has also been pushing
for.
>> Guys, thanks so much. A lot to consider
here this morning. Brooke, Jennifer
Ramson. Appreciate it. Coming up on
Morning Brief, we'll bring you today's
top trending tickers as we count you
down to the opening bell. Don't go
anywhere.
[Music]
And now time for some today's trending
tickers. We are watching Lithium
America's Oracle and Acadia Pharma.
First up, Lithium Americas. Those shares
are surging following reports that the
Trump administration is pursuing a stake
in the company. The White House proposed
taking equity in the lithium producer
during a renegotiation of the terms of a
$2.3 billion loan extended by the energy
department. That's according to
Bloomberg. Those shares are surging by
66% and we're seeing a lift to some
other lithium miners as well. Next up,
Oracle. The company reportedly looking
to raise $15 billion from corporate bond
sales. According to Bloomberg, the
software maker is selling debt in as
many as seven parts, including a rare
40-year bond. The deal comes as Oracle
begins to fulfill massive cloud
infrastructure deals with OpenAI and
Meta, which are boosting the company's
expenses. In the next several years,
it's projected to spend hundreds of
billions of dollars to rent and power
data centers. And finally, Aadia Pharma.
Those shares are sinking after the drug
makers rare disease drug trial failed.
The latest stage trial of its
investigative therapy to help treat
hyperphasia did to did not meet its
primary endpoint. Stifel analysts say
the trial failure removes one of the
potential upside drivers for that stock
and those shares down 12%. Meanwhile,
shares of Seleno Therapeutics, which
currently markets a drug to treat
hyperphasia, did jump on the news. As
always, you can scan the QR code below
to track the best and worst performing
stocks with Yahoo Finance's trending
tickers page. Well, big AI names took
some losses during trade Wednesday with
Nvidia and Oracle recovering pre-market
after both closing lower. My next guest
says announcements of major deals
between those companies and OpenAI could
be fueling what he calls a potentially
epic bubble. Joining us now is Joe
Heganner, Astrazoa Capital CIO. Joe,
thanks for being here.
>> Thanks for having me.
>> So, it's been really interesting to
follow this AI trade. We've seen, as I
was talking about earlier in the show,
sort of the waxing and waning of
sentiment, right? This is going to be
the biggest thing ever. How could it
possibly be? Oh, all these companies are
spending money. they're spending too
much money with, you know, so it seems
like we're in another one of those
waning or at least questioning phases.
Is that fair to say? And and do you
think it's valid to question the whole
uh structure of the thing?
>> Well, I definitely think it's valid to
question uh the overall structure and
the phenomenon that's taking place. Um
you know, we're we're drawing a lot of
similarities between what's happening
now and of course.com. That's not
necessarily a new reference. Um, but the
thing I think is particularly
interesting, right, is just the timing
of of market bubbles and what what's
brings them to a halt, I suppose, right?
You the dot era, the only thing that
really popped or burst that bubble was
the Fed raising interest rates, right?
And and um kind of
>> that led to, you know, the epic crash.
But for years there were commentators
and professionals and analysts from 1995
all the way to 2000 that were pounding
the table saying we're in a bubble.
We're in a bubble. And they were right.
But if you got short in 1995, right? You
know, you weren't you didn't exist by
the 1999 and you missed out on 40% plus
equity market returns for for years to
come. And so that's the interesting
thing I think that's taking place now is
I definitely think we are in a bubble.
Uh and so you know what do you do at
this stage, right? Because we just cut
interest rates and we're looking at
cutting more and there's fiscal spending
coming down the pike,
>> right? So there's nothing externally
necessarily that would burst the bubble.
>> If anything, I feel like we're about to
pour some gasoline on the fire and um
and so that's what gives us a little bit
of pause because I definitely think the
the left tail scenario, the the risk to
the downside is immense because by any
measure valuations are very stretched.
We're seeing all sorts of these circular
deals that we saw in 1998, 1999 with
some of the same players as we're seeing
today. Um, and yet it's very difficult
for me to actually get bearish right now
because there are so many positive
catalysts as it relates to um kind of
pushing this sentiment towards more uh
extreme levels.
>> So, and you're on the credit side of the
equation, right?
>> Mostly mostly on the credit side. Yes.
>> So, how do you then play it? I mean, and
you mentioned some of the same players
like Oracle, which you know, experienced
the bust in the dotcom era, but they're
still around and they're back and
they're bigger than ever. Like, do you
go in I we just talked about their bond
sale. Do you go in and is that an
attractive offering?
>> Uh, well, I would argue absolutely not,
but um but it's just not necessarily
anything to do with Oracle. It's just a
function of credit spreads broadly right
now are the near the lowest they've ever
been in history. and and it does look
like we're seeing some macroeconomic
deterioration in you know jobs data and
things along those lines and you know a
$15 billion investment grade issuance at
sofur plus 40 basis points is just not
compelling to us
>> I I want to just translate that for
people who are not steeped in the in the
credit market. So basically, you are not
getting paid
>> exactly
>> as an investor to make these investments
right now is another way to put that.
>> You're getting paid Yes. Exactly. Right.
You're getting paid 40 extra basis
points per year in yield over treasuries
to assume the credit risk of of a
corporation that could not exist in 10
years from now. And it's very difficult
to say. I mean, if you had if you asked
me or any professional in 1995 if you
thought Blackberry was going to be
around in 10 years, I mean, most people
would probably say they'll for sure be
around. And there's just there's all
sorts of things that could happen over
the long haul. And so when you're
thinking about credit risk in
particular, you just want to be a little
bit more discerning. Um, and so the way
that we're kind of looking at that or
playing that is
>> we're actually playing mostly on a
relative value basis. And so, you know,
we can buy credit default swaps that
effectively would be you'd be short the
the the credits that you don't like.
>> So, you're basically buying insurance
against the company defaulting on its
debt at some point.
>> Exactly. The beautiful thing about that
instrument is that the lower credit
spreads go, the smaller your insurance
premium is for the protection. And so,
as they get lower and lower and more and
more compressed, it costs us less and
less to buy. It's that old saying,
right? Buy insurance when you don't
think you need it. And so how do you end
up making money on those then?
>> Well, it's a relative value. That's a
great question, right? So if you if you
give me $100 and I buy $100 worth of
bonds and the yield on that is eight or
nine%, I'm happy to take one or 2% perom
of that to purchase protection on the
credits that I don't like.
>> Gotcha. Okay. So um so that's how you're
looking at things right now. How do
yield how do does what the Fed is doing,
how does that feed into all of this?
>> Oh gosh. um you know
>> in 20 seconds. No, I'm just
>> Yeah. So, uh I think that there's Yeah,
I think there's an enormous amount of
risk over the intermediate to longer
term as it relates to the shape of the
yield curve. Um in terms of the polarity
that seems to exist within the Federal
Reserve right now. There are a handful
of people, and I'm kind of in this camp,
too. I think it's very hard to argue
that financial conditions are tight when
crypto is going parabolic and equity
markets are all-time highs and there's
um what did Powell say in his presser
the other day? It was effectively
Greenspan's version of a rational
exuberant stock valuations are elevated.
I think he said
>> um the jobs data while deteriorating
it's unclear to me how much of that is a
function of efficiency and productivity
gains. Right? If I'm a law firm and I
don't need the 100 analysts anymore
because I have AI embedded tools and I
don't hire as much, I'm immensely more
productive and my equity value is
actually going to be significantly
higher, but the jobs data is going to be
weaker,
>> right? And so these there are structural
structural changes that are taking place
in the economy that could lead to weak
economic data or weak jobs data, but it
doesn't necessarily imply that changing
the interest rate at the Federal Reserve
overnight rate is going to do anything
to adjust that or fix that. If anything,
you're just going to pour gasoline on
that fire.
>> So you think there's a risk to them
continuing to cut rates?
>> Yes, definitely. And I think we'll see
that. And if if if that is correct,
we'll we'll continue to see the yield
curve steepen, the long end of the curve
start to go higher and higher as the
front end comes down.
>> And that also to your earlier point
makes the maybe extends the bubble even
further.
>> Yes, I I do. And I do also think if the
long end of the curve continues to march
higher, we'll see some sort of uh yield
curve control via Bessant or or maybe
even the Federal Reserve who you know
Trump's going to install the new Fed
chair in not too long of a time from
now. Um and he's already had significant
influence on you know who's who the
board of governors are, right?
>> And so it could be a very different
Federal Reserve in a year from now than
the one we're seeing today.
>> And just briefly, yield curve control.
How what would that look like? Well,
there's a number of ways to play that
out, but effectively, right, but there's
um you would a government or a central
bank would implement that if they don't
like long end the the trajectory of long
end interest rates, right? The Fed can
only control the overnight rate and then
the rest of the curve is extrapolated
out via markets.
>> But you can take a bazooka and go buy
hundreds of billions of dollars worth of
30-year Treasury bonds and force the
30-year rate lower. Um you could also
and this is OB they've already mentioned
this publicly you could uh deregulate
the banks to where you could encourage
or facilitate uh you know the large
banks in the US to uh purchase be
purchasers of uh long end treasury bonds
to increase demand to lower interest
rates. There's a number of tweaks and
and if anybody's going to do it Scott
Besset is the guy. um you know he
understands capital markets so well that
um if you know if he wants lower rates
I'm not necessarily going to bet against
him because he's got a lot of levers at
his disposal.
>> Okay, got to leave it there. Joe, thank
you so much. Interesting. All right,
coming up on Yahoo Finance Opening Bid,
our executive editor Brian Sazi is
joining us now to give us a little
preview. What's coming up?
>> Uh Julie, uh really interesting chat
there. I thoroughly enjoyed all the chat
on credit. But as for opening bid, I am
staying on the AI trade. I think this
notion that uh we are near peak AI capex
needs to be completely tossed in the
trash. Look at that good news out of
Micron Alibaba overnight. Good stuff
indeed, Julie.
>> Looking forward to it. Thanks, S. That
does it for morning brief. Much more
ahead on Yahoo Finance.